[Music]
Hello. Hey, how's it going? Welcome.
Hey, thanks for having me, Dion. Of
course. It's a pleasure being here.
Where are you coming from, actually?
Yeah, I'm drilling in from Egypt, Cairo.
Oh, nice. Well, thanks so much. Uh
that's uh a little bit later than here
even. So thanks for thanks for this. Uh
yeah, thanks. I'm really excited. Yeah.
Awesome. Well, I'm gonna I'm gonna get
off the stage myself and hand it over
for you and get your slides up and then
we can get going and and go from there.
So have a great chat. Great. Thanks,
Dion. So reliable DevOps agents for
self-driving infrastructure. So let me
tell you a bit about myself. So I was a
founding engineer at a couple of other
startups. Always building infrastructure
and doing like the security work. Um so
I've been writing code for 10 years now.
Um I really like doing calisthenics like
body weightight exercises riding
cruisers and like volunteering teaching
people like how to code and how to do
infrastructure. Um I really like like
developer security developer experience
and security which are usually two
things that never mix well. uh well the
yeah app that's what I'm mostly
interested in so let me tell you a bit
first about the problem like why is this
necessary like why do we need the
self-driving infrastructure in the first
place so today we've been interviewing
engineers like developers software
engineers and engineering leaders like
hundreds of them every year since we
started stack because like as you
guessed it like we're working on trying
to make infrastructure self-driving with
like reliable configurations and agents
which are things like that don't mix
like security and developer experience
so like agent and reliability. Uh like
how do you explain it? So here like I
grouped a lot of the feedback we got
from different people into like fixious
three personas. So DevOps engineers see
that developers have no clue what
they're doing. So they don't know a lot
of things about the system internals of
all the DevOps tools of all the complex
infrastructure they deploy their apps
on. At the same time, platform engineers
are sick of spending the majority of
their time on support tickets instead of
doing platform work that optimizes costs
or like makes the de developers life
much easier. On the other side,
developers like they see a huge mismatch
or like misalignment in in priorities.
So developers want to get this bucket or
like get this feature out. They want
this to work while DevOps or like the
infrastructure or platform team want to
move to Kubernetes. Um so like there's a
lot of misaligned like priorities and a
lot of like bottlenecks in the
infrastructure and this pain keeps
growing even with internal developer
platforms and the abstractions people
are building to make this thing easier.
And the reason this is so tough is
because there are like hundreds of DSLs
like a different configuration
parameters and languages and schemas
that you need to learn to figure this
out. So we call this DSL hell like
domain specific language hell. It's not
just the DSLs but also the schemas
themselves configuring. So like YAML is
sort of like a data language or DSL but
then there's like hundreds of ways of
writing YAML to configure all these
tools. So you're not just writing a
programming language and building stuff,
but you're configuring other tools and
these tools have internal top secret
information about how they operate and
you need to be aware of that to be able
to write these tools. So it's like a
very minority like the minority of
developers understand these tools really
well and understand all the different
combinations and I've rarely seen a
DevOps engineer infrastructure person
understands all of them but like always
a subset. So that's one reason why this
is very difficult. a lot of things to
learn and to you have to keep in your
mind to be able to do this kind of work.
Another thing is that most of the
abstractions in this like we have layers
of abstractions in infrastructure and
they're all almost all of them are
leaky. So for example if you're trying
to create a plot on Kubernetes and set a
limit. So limit is a contract with
resources you allocate to a specific
workload you're running and then you
would see like you expect or like most
developers expect that this limit would
be honored by the platform. But then
what happens? They find their pod or
workload killed because it's ran out of
memory and they can't correlate that
this is has to do with the limits. So
like the underlying layer that operates
the workload just kills it if it exceeds
the limit. Um so this is leak caps
action. So developers have to keep in
mind how this thing works internally how
like the kublet like runs the like the
container or like there's workload and
how it deals with the memory limits. The
same thing goes with corner cases for
dockerization. Like cloud native build
packs are amazing and people build
internal Docker files in a reusable way
so people can keep building the same
apps over and over again but they rarely
work because of all the corner cases.
Same thing with something like
Terraform. You have the underlying layer
that communicates with infrastructure
like Google cloud just made an upbrupt
API change that just broke a lot of
Terraform code that is with Google. So
these are some of the difficulties we
see but also people keep talking about
it. So in real life experience like
people keep complaining about LLMs are
decent at writing code but they suck at
infrastructure which is like the worst
part of coding setup and infrastructure.
And this guy here like after posting
this with after a month later he just
like throw decided to throw in the towel
and say okay AGI is here once an agent
can configure a do container setup CI
and deploy my app. That's how
frustrating it is. But like these are
all opinions and like subjective um like
subjective opinions of why LLMs and like
are suck at this kind of work. But like
there's a paper about one of the reasons
they are terrible at this work and it's
because they suck at domain specific
languages and configuration in general.
So from this paper you can see like a
trend here where LMS are really good at
very popular languages that change not
very frequently over the years um versus
other languages like the long tail of
DSLs and the longtail of non-popular
languages anymore they're not that good
at it at the same time when you see like
the stack valene the two data sets in
this like paper which compares like
asking about fresh knowledge versus old
knowledge the LMS were already trained
on they perform really bad like on fresh
knowledge and this is the mix we get in
DevOps tasks. So if you're trying to
compare coding tasks and DevOps tasks on
like some factors based on like
everything we discussed so far you'll
see that the feedback loop for coding
tasks is super tight. So you get like
when you have a coding agent and there's
a human in the loop and it changes
something you see it you can validate
the code and then keep iterating
quicker. But for DevOps task it's
usually much longer. So you're trying to
create a virtual machine or database on
AWS and you have to wait for like for 15
minutes at least for it to be ready. So
then you would know if you created it
with the right parameters for example.
So like this is dumb example but like
you get the idea. The feedback loop is
super slow. Another thing that's
different between regular coding tasks
and DevOps tasks is like the user
knowledge. So users or coders like or
developers using these coded assisting
coding assistants they have high
knowledge of the task at hand which is
writing code. But less than 3% of
developers are expert at this kind of
infrastructure work. At least three less
than 3% do this full-time. Also, the
syntax for coding tasks is super popular
compared to many domain specific
languages and the frequency of this
changes like coding languages change
rarely like the syntax and the features
unlike other DevOps tool configurations
because the tools keep changing quickly.
They add features and these
configuration languages configure the
tools. So the more tools the more
complexity the harder it is. And final
thing is about the context itself. So
most of the context you find for coding
tasks is local. So it's such like you're
developing locally in your machine. So
everything you need or almost everything
you need can be run locally or mocked
locally. But for DevOps task is super
hard because the context is mostly
remote like a bucket or configurations
through AWS API or like Kubernetes
clusters deployed in production with a
specific set of parameters or workloads
that are not available locally. So this
is the reason why LM agents or like
coding agents are really good at coding.
but they suck at infrastructure or
DevOps work. So what usually happens is
they like run out of steam like keep
going around in loops or they're unable
to accomplish these tasks and like this
is our analysis of like at least what we
learned over the past couple of years.
So self-driving infrastructure, a lot of
people see it this way, like cybermen
from Doctor Who, like they're going to
take over humanity basically like push
humans out and be more efficient, be
more like stronger when it comes to
doing these kind of infrastructure
tests. But like from my experience,
we're developing agents and how we see
them operate with think self-driving
infrastructure is going to be something
like this with a lot of minions that are
stoastic agents. They sometimes spit out
gibberish and they do funny things like
they keep walking around but like when
effectively managed and guided they can
accomplish great things like they get
the job done really well with human
guidance but they're a force like to be
reckoned with. So in here like today
we're going to talk about like how we're
working on this. First I'm trying to
help you imagine what a self-driving
infrastructure would look like with
these kind of minions. But when you're
thinking about agents that operate
infrastructure, like I want you to
picture minions, not cyber. So what
would self-driving infrastructure look
like? So theoretically, a self-driving
infrastructure would have these
capabilities at least. So the first
thing is you would have agents that work
24/7. So these agents can do maintenance
tasks in the background. They can handle
support tickets. They can tune your
system live 24/7 without having people
on call. And you'll be able to keep
doing that over and over again. Second
thing is this self-driving
infrastructure or be technology agnostic
as we mentioned earlier like having a
lot of tools and a lot of providers with
different semantics and different ways
of describing things make things super
difficult. So having these self-driving
infrastructure capabilities it shouldn't
like the this self-driving
infrastructure shouldn't care about like
the the tools it's using or the cloud
provider it should operate across them
and like orchestrate across the
different cloud providers and
technologies easily. The third thing is
you have a dynamic platform UI. So as
you can see with VIP coding like you can
build simple applications and interfaces
really quickly or prototype more complex
stuff really quickly and the same thing
would be happening in a self-driving
infrastructure within your internal
tools. So internal tools would keep
evolving. They would keep changing
depending on the use cases which fixes a
huge problem we have with like internal
developer platforms today which is like
static abstractions and these
abstractions like they have to keep
evolving. But instead of having a
product manager and a developer that
like put a lot of effort into
maintaining this and keep changing them
because they can't change it at the same
rate that developers would expect the
platform capabilities to evolve. So this
can be done automatically autonomously.
And finally two major very important
things we haven't tapped. So like we
have super complicated infrastructure
service with a lot of great capabilities
but we still don't have that much like
intelligence in cost optimization and
scaling. So what this would entail like
imagine the scenario like you're running
a workload the Kubernetes cluster but
then the self-driving infrastructure
would detect that this workload is like
while monitoring the data is more suited
for something serverless. So it would
move it from your EKS cluster to Lambda
for a specific duration with zero
downtime because this is the most
appropriate kind of like compute
platform to run your workload on. So
this would help you reduce costs
dramatically and help you with scaling
depending on this. So you wouldn't care
anymore about like the underlying
compute because your infrastructure is
going to be able to migrate itself like
move these workloads around to save
costs and optimize scaling whenever you
you have to deal with it. So things like
scaling to Lambda and then going back to
Kubernetes or scaling to zero would be
easy and it wouldn't care about the
underlying compute platform
specifications because these things can
be self-driving. So let me give you some
examples of how this how this would look
in practice with a couple of use cases
from different
personas. So having these agents run
24/7 you can do things like routine
maintenance and not the trivial kind of
routine maintenance something like this.
So if you have ever had to upgrade
Kubernetes after like months like you
get a new Kubernetes version every three
uh three months but like imagine you
spend a year or two like not upgrading
these Kubernetes clusters and then you
have to do it all at once. So you would
prompt this self-driving infrastructure
to upgrade my EKS cluster to the latest
Kubernetes version available and then it
would come up with a plan on how to do
this sequentially because you cannot do
it at the same time and if you're using
infrastructures code like terraform and
you're trying to do that it would fail
like it's not able to do this kind of
incremental upgrades autonomously. So
the agent will be able to do that. So
the self-driving infrastructure will
take this instruction, go to the
cluster, read the documentation that
changed up between the different
versions, migrate your workloads, test
it, make sure everything is great,
upgrade the like API server and keep
doing that until you reach the latest
version. And this will be able to like
this will be done can be done overnight.
So you don't have to monitor it. You
don't have to like keep guiding it on
how to fix this issues. It will be able
to figure it out. And this is what
agents are great at like figuring out
like new unpaved roads to like
accomplish a specific goal. So this is
one
thing. Another thing would be
intelligent abstractions. So this is
like something really painful like so
different cloud providers have different
ways of like naming a a firewall. So the
firewall is some sort of like a high
level became a high level user intent.
So if I'm a security engineer and I
faced this before like and I'm trying to
figure out okay where are like the
firewall rules where all inbound traffic
is like allowed within the cluster or
like within my environment and I'll just
ask it this and it would be able to
figure out like translate the highle
intent into lower level um executable
operation and figure out okay a firewall
in an AWS like in AWS is called a
security group at digital ocean it's
called a firewall and on like Google
compute it's called or Google cloud it's
the firewall. So we'll be able to figure
this out and aggregate the results
across different clouds like in a hybrid
environment and show them to me without
having to break this down and without
having to define a rigid abstraction. So
this is what I meant of like having more
intelligent abstractions. Um another
kind of example is keep trying while we
sleep. So if you're trying to remember
when I mentioned like creating docker
templates, docker file templates or
using cloud native build packs don't
work in every single environment in
every single case because applications
are not identical. So this is a great
application for self-driving
infrastructure. It will be able to
containerize an app, work on iterating,
coming up with a plan, creating progress
checklist, keep iterating on cont, but
like not just spitting out a docker
file, but actually building the image,
running it, and testing the health check
to make sure it passes and figuring out
issues along the way. So you can see
from this screenshot the sub my
self-driving infrastructure is able to
read a compos file to test the docker
file that's running properly spins up a
database locally configures all the
variables all the secrets to make sure
the app is working fine before spitting
out the final docker file. So it's not
just like previously generating
configurations but actually validating
that these configurations work and a
self-driving infrastructure wouldn't be
compete with VIP deploy. So you can
already try any of the existing like
coding agents to do vibe deploys on
different environments. But the cool
thing here is these are context
specific. So you're able to vive deploy
on your own custom infrastructure on
your cloud account and it will follow
security best practices. So this is the
tough part like not just vibe deploying
anywhere but by deploying in your own
environment with security best
practices. So here I'm asking the
self-driving infrastructure agent to
deploy an app on my AWS account with TLS
configured and to configure a specific
domain to point to it and it goes
through this and figures out everything.
And if you can see like it's pretty tiny
but like when it's configuring the
database here it didn't like create a
plain text like password and spit it
plain text into like the terminal but
created in a file and used this file to
add the password to the API without
having to expose this in a shell and it
created a secure password like a long
enough password so it and configured TLS
and added a systemd file to restart on
server restarts and this is like there's
a lot of details involved in like vibe
deploying or like vibe ops um as Ray
Myers called it. Um so there's a lot of
details and getting these properly
within your environment is hard. I mean
even developers struggle with this today
because they don't have all the details
and all the things they should do right
at the same time in their brains when
they're trying to do this. So it's super
tough. So the cool thing about this
example, this is already possible today.
So this is not the
future. Self-driving infrastructure
agents or DevOps agents are able to do
this today. But is it reliable enough?
Which is the biggest question. So like
if you're going to try having a
self-driving infrastructure with these
capabilities like how reliable are
agents today and how can you make them
better like how can you make be sure
that you can sleep at night while the
agent is up self upgrading your
Kubernetes cluster with zero downtime
because this is a very tough thing to
do. So to talk more about like how we
think about reliability and what we've
learned so far making these agents
reliable in a very critical task like
building a self-driving infrastructure
let me share with you how we think of an
agent. So, welcome Norbert. So, this is
one of the minions we've been building
or experimenting with and it's the
simplest possible agent. So, Norbert, as
you can see, like the naked minion, it
thinks and then it takes one of two
actions. So, just like very simple
actions and that's the first thing an
agent can do. Like an agent can
autonomously decide which action to
take. So, it can be two actions which is
the minimum. So, it has some choice or
it can be many
actions. Um the second thing is after it
takes an action it affects the external
world. So it has some way of modeling
the external world or observing the
effects of its actions. So it can
iterate which is the second thing of
making an agent. So the agent can take
actions autonomously, choose which
actions and it iterates, keeps taking
actions to accomplish a specific goal.
That's the third component. An agent
should have an end goal or somehow a
measurable end goal to be able to to
evaluate its reliability. Otherwise,
it's super hard to say if the agent is
done and super hard to say if the agent
accomplished its task successfully. So
this is not as easy for every single
domain. So in our domain we're fortunate
enough is like if you're trying to
containerize an app or like deploy
something or debug something you can
find in a deterministic way like
validate that the agent accomplished its
goal but like things like documentation
generation is much harder for example or
writing is much harder. So in this case
having an angle um in this in these
agents makes it easier to evaluate their
reliability and make them better or like
at least be able to observe this to see
how we can improve it. So getting this
out of the way, how we define agents.
Agent takes actions, it iterates until
it reaches a specific end goal. So how
we think about reliability, we split
agents into two parts. You see there's
the think part which is the first thing
we're trying to make it reliable. So how
it thinks, how it comes up with tools or
like actions to take and the other part
are the actions themselves because you
can have as many actions as you want.
And we found out that the actions like
the performance of the actions
themselves affect the agent a
dramatically. So like the the the impact
of having action like the the choice of
actions and how intelligent these
actions are like how for example like
you can have a very simple action that
does a lot of things or like specific
actions dedicated to stuff and there's
there's a trade-off because the more
tools you act add the harder it is for
the agent to come up with the right
combination of tools to execute sim to a
human being like if you give a human
being too many options like you can
their brains will just overload and like
you get decision fatigue. So the same
thing happens to agents. So we're
splitting it between reliable thinking
and reliable actions or reliable tools.
Let's start with reliable thinking. So
when we're talking about reliable
thinking of the agent is how it comes up
like after observing the external
environment um or like the distilled
version of the external environment in
its memory um like what actions would it
take and in which order. So reliable
thinking is more focused on the brain
and when you're thinking on the brain we
came up of like in the literature you
would see three ways of evaluating
success. So you can check the end goal
which is the easier the most
straightforward way because if the agent
doesn't accomplish the end task like
it's failed like it couldn't build an
app that runs or like couldn't migrate
your kubernetes cluster or couldn't
deploy stuff on ECS or couldn't contain
app. So it's it's relatively easier to
reason about the end goal because this
is the task we're trying to accomplish.
But then some people use sub goals
because sometimes the end goal keep
failing and you're not sure why. So if
you divide things into sub goals you get
a better idea of why the end goal is not
accomplished. So this is another way to
measure success. And finally, the most
complicated way to measure success is
the action trajectory. So the agent
takes specific sequence of actions given
a specific input. So a snapshot of the
real world or like the snapshot of its
memory or state and then it takes
specific actions based on this like kind
of snapshot and then you evaluate this
like is this the right course of action
given the initial starting parameters
which can be fixed. Um so this is
another way to measure like the the
evaluating success. So at stack we still
haven't gone through like all three.
We've been doing a lot of work with end
goals and sub goals but we still haven't
started evaluating trajectories yet but
it's something on the road map something
want to dig deeper in because there are
a lot of common like subtasks that are
very common between different kinds of
infrastructure devops tasks. So it would
be great to see like how trajectory of
agents perform on these specific like
sub goals or
like sub trajectories.
So since now we can like evaluate like
the success criteria. We know when the
agent is successful we can we have to
pick specific metrics because we're
trying to evaluate how reliable the
thinking process is. So some of the
metrics we people use that are generic
enough and you can apply to different
domains like these kind of like the
evaluation criteria. You can also apply
this to different domains not like
DevOps or infrastructure specific is
pass K which means if you give the agent
K attempts uh what's the likelihood
that's going to succeed at least once.
So K at one is the likelihood that this
agent is going to succeed like on a
single try at K at four is the
likelihood that this agent is going to
succeed at least once given four
attempts. Um, so this is a very good
indicator of can the agent actually
accomplish what it was designed to do or
not. So this basically asks that like is
the agent capable of doing this or not.
But it doesn't measure reliability
because if the agent is capable of doing
something everyone in like 10 trials
doesn't mean like every single user or
every single time we're going to do this
it's going to pass. And this is very
difficult for very security like very
critical infrastructure tasks. So there
is also pass power k or pass a k which
means like given k attempts what is the
like the likelihood that the agent would
pass k times. So assuming like pass to
the power of k is pass the power four.
So given four attempts what's the
likelihood that the agent is going to
pass four times which measures more
reliability and it's a tougher metric to
hit. The other thing we measure is the
number of steps because we notice that
the more steps the agent does, the more
it tends to hallucinate and the longer
it takes it to accomplish the task. So
if there's something critical I want to
recover, for example, from a failed
deployment or roll back or fix something
that you can do reliably with a
deterministic system and you need an
agent, the agent finishing its job
quickly is a great thing. Like it's the
desirable thing. At the same time, if
you're not doing a lot of state or
context compression and you want to keep
steps, the more steps you add, the
larger the context blows up and the more
likely the agent will listen hallucinate
and lose track of what it's trying to
do. So, it's like like dangling a banana
in front of a minion. So, the minion
when see when it sees the banana, it
will just abandon the task and chase the
banana because it's just overwhelmed and
it sees something interesting and just
chase. So, the agents that do a lot of
steps and keep a lot of steps in their
memory, they tend to lose track of what
we're trying to do in the first place.
And the same thing happens to me
sometimes. But that's why we measure the
number of steps. So the final thing is
the cost of success which like how much
would it cost us for an contization
agent to be able to dockerize an app
successfully because as you see like it
can take on a contization process and
take 15 minutes and I can like if the
success rate is 50% I could just like
run it 10 times overnight until it's
successful which is fine but how much
would it cost me? Like because what if
it costs me $2,000 or like $10,000 to
container as an app, then it doesn't
make sense anymore. So part of the
problems being solved is the cost of the
problem itself. Like would it cost more
than it would save us to do this kind of
task? Like if you have a big migration
project that would spend three years
modernizing your infrastructure and like
this thing is going like the
self-driving infra like DevOps agents is
going to cut this down into 80 months
like would the cost of doing so be like
given the time and everything like would
it be worth it or not. So this is an
example table of one of the very first
evaluations we built. So the task here
was being able to deploy um and like a
full stack application on AWS, a
statefell application on AWS with like
all the bells and whistles and with all
the security best practices including
TLS, secure passwords, private database,
bottomup security groups, stuff like
that. So here we tried different
applications with different technology
stacks trying to make it as diverse as
possible and we measured passet one and
measured passet 4 and you can see here
like we also added some custom metrics
which is something you might do like
adding custom metrics specific here. So
here we wanted developers to see how
fast it is to deploy these apps. So we
added in the mix like a deployment time.
So depending on the evaluation the kind
of metrics and success criteria I shared
are very generic but you can also add in
the mix like very specific things. So
once we got this we found out like two
um like two major takeaways. The first
one is sometimes the success rate is
really high and it's really fast and it
doesn't mean like okay so this kind of
task like it's really good at it. So
it's very reliable. It's almost as if
it's deterministic. Um, so this is
great. So this agent is great. Like we
didn't need to optimize further for this
kind of like specific task. But in other
tasks, we found out that the passet one
is very low, but the passet four is much
higher. Like as you see here, like if we
give it four attempts, it would go up
from 50% to just like 39 uh 93%. Which
is very high. Like you can afford to do
this in every task. Like some tasks like
dockerization like it's not very
critical. You can leave it doing that
overnight. Try over and over again. And
every trial is just an hour which is
amazing like it would take me four hours
to deploy this kind of app. Um but here
we can afford it but not all
applications we can afford this. So pass
four can be tricky like pass K can be
tricky uh in very critical situations
and then you need to do the pass power K
to make sure it's consistent and
reliable because you don't want to rely
on agent in something critical and then
you find out like it's just like
hallucinated or like broken
infrastructure or something. So not not
always like pass can be like misleading
in some cases but yeah you get it. So
the big like the big elephant in the
room especially for infrastructure and
devops task like there's no available
public data sets or like very few data
sets and with a lot of stale data uh out
there. So how do we evaluate without
data points like how we gather these
data points. So the first thing we
started is like aggregating open source
code on GitHub for infrastructure. But
unfortunately for our domain like most
of the code is super old and it's
outdated and it's not like as high
quality as you would see and it doesn't
represent the actual fact because like
infrastructure configurations people
don't usually put that on GitHub like
they keep it in private repositories um
for their infrastructure and they're
like like it's a closely guard kind
guarded kind of code for any
organization. So this is terrible like
we weren't able to rely on this much but
it gives us a hint and then we do a
synthetic data like we generate a lot of
synthetic data like running the agents
generating code and using these to build
the valves and they're surprisingly
really well because really good because
for very complex task even a human like
doesn't have like 100% success rate. So
synthetic data it like the success rate
is like 70%. This would exactly be the
like the success rate if you give a
human the same time to the data set. But
the highest quality of data you can get
is from real customer support cases. So
we take this cases, we study them and
then we analyze it like generate go back
to generate synthetic data based on
these cases like guided synthetic data
and these are the high quality we can
get and we always start seating these
data evaluation data sets with
handcrafted data. So like we create use
cases manually um to try to spread it
like to handle corner cases and stuff
like that um which is like the highest
quality data we can get but we don't get
a lot of quantity like a higher quantity
of this kind of data. So something else
we do like this is for the evaluation
but what should you do after production
um so we use a lot of LM like we tried a
lot of LM observity tools they're all
pretty much the same we use length views
at the moment so length use like it
gives you like kind sort of traces for
like the L&M workflow so if you have
complex workflows or agent you can track
everything like all the prompts all the
sequence the input and the output and so
on and then you can see when something
goes wrong you would extract samples
from this like production observability
data and and add it as a
handcrafted data point to your
evaluation data. So this is very
important not just to understand what's
going on in production but also be able
to refine the evaluation data and keep
like building this flywheel making these
agents better and better and more
reliable. So this is the first part
reliable thinking or like how to make
the agent thinking process better.
Another part is reliable tools because
we're huge advocates of the approach
that like we're trying to have very few
but super high quality tools and we
found out that these make the agents
much much smarter compared to very dumb
tools. So instead of the agent taking
like 20 steps to reach a specific
conclusion or like do something they can
just do a single step which keeps like
the context from blowing up and it keeps
the agents much simpler by like
offloading or like delegating these
tasks to a more capable workflow or a
tool. So here I'm going to show you a
couple of examples uh of how we're
evaluating tools because eval tools is
trickier than agents because um so it's
sort of like it's easier to get like to
build an eval data uh for for this like
for for tools but it's harder to come up
with like success metrics because they
vary greatly like every single tool has
its own success criteria and and metrics
to measure it with. So for the context
retrieval evaluation like here we're
trying to retrieve specific parts of
your infrastructure that are relevant to
a question or to do precise like
surgical edits to accomplish a specific
task. And here you can see like we use a
recall because we are optimizing for the
amount of information you retrieve for
the context in your machine like in your
environment. Um in another case for code
generation for example and Terraform
specifically we can't just like validate
the quality of the code. We want to make
sure this code is appliable in
production. So we have a metric that
measures zero shot terraform planning
success rate. So we take the code we
actually try apply it in a sandbox
environment and see if it succeeds and
then or like at least plan it against
this environment and see if it succeeds.
And this is like a high enough bar I
think so far at least so far for
Terapform code generation. Um and this
is basically how we evaluated this two
call. So as you can see like two calls
have like you have to be creative on how
you evaluate every single tool call
because like and how much how important
this specific task is. So you can
distribute your like weight or like
amount of work evenly so you can like
deal with the lowest hanging fruit
first, but then like add specific like
harder requirements and harder as you're
accomplishing more scores. So the more
higher scores we reach on specific like
uh metrics we're evaluating tools at the
harder we're trying to make the metric
or the goal so we can keep keep them
getting better and more reliable. So
that's it. But as you guessed so far
from this Cyberman, I'm a huge fan of
science fiction. And I found this quote
very relevant from like the one of the
very famous like um books written so far
on robotics and AI by Isaac Kazimov and
it says like there was a time when
humanity faced the universe alone and
without a friend, but now they have
creatures to help them. And these little
like minion kind of agent guys, they're
super helpful and super funny,
especially when it comes to some like
very dull and a very like painful kind
of work developers have to deal with
with infrastructure. So this is a great
chance to try control these features and
like make them better so we can sleep
better at night and like we can enjoy
coding
again. Thank you so much. So please
reach out if you're interested in
discussing this more. Uh, I would love
to show you what we're doing and talk
about these kind of like agent evals
because they're super tough and they're
super interesting. So, yeah, this is my
LinkedIn. Thank you.
Thank you so much, George. That was
awesome. Um,
yeah, that that was really fun. It
resonated a lot. And right at the end
there with the Azimoff quote, like I
recently had a project where I had to
hack on something for a couple weeks and
it was just me and me and some bots and
it felt different than back in the old
days or like I feel like I've got like a
bit of a thought partner and I like
write up like many specs, send it off to
uh to my minions uh in that case to do
work and it was a very different
experience than kind of doing it
solitary. I do like working with humans,
so I like having
both. I don't just want to be locked
away in the basement, but uh yeah, it's
really um so on before you go, I got a
couple questions here. So, this is one
uh have you considered using
reinforcement learning techniques to
guide these agents and potentially
improve their success rate compared to
relying on on rules and like any
thoughts there? Yes, definitely. Yeah,
definitely. Like one of the major
challenges with the agents is picking
like at least the evaluating like or
improving the thinking part. Like we
talked only about evaluation like not
techniques to improve the performance
but like one of the major things with
thinking is choosing the right tool at
the right time. And this is where like
reinforcement learning policies are
super important. Like you can yeah like
you can optimize the tool choice based
on like successful runs. But like the
trick here is figuring out like how to
create a reward function that optimizes
for like the success rate. Like would
you incorporate like there are some
papers they incorporate a mix of have
like taking the end goal and the process
at the same time and like add a mix it
like a a weighted sum for like
accomplishing sub goals and end goals
for example in the reward policy but
also you need a lot of good data points
to be able to train this. Yeah. So this
is definitely something we're
considering and working on. Yeah. Yeah.
I kind of picture like having minions in
these isolated worlds to be able to try
things out and be able to kind of learn
over time and and do the uh do the alpha
zero um thing but in the world of DevOps
that's really fun but it's super slow
like we have cloud sandboxes and we let
these agents like we have a minion farm
where these agents are strong freely but
like it takes sometimes like 15 or like
up to 60 minutes to accomplish a
specific task which is super slow to
generate an update Yeah, enough
realistic data. Oh man, that's fun. So,
if if I'm newer to this world, like how
do I build the trust to the point that I
can actually sleep at night and allow
this system to go off and be, you know,
self-healing and doing things and not
having me, you know, have my mind wake
myself up at 2 am worrying about, you
know, what happened? How do you kind of
go through and build that trust?
So, we have two things at the moment.
We're still discovering like we're still
exploring this but like one of the thing
we found out that really helped and is
like showing the users or like the
developers the thought process of how it
comes up to these conclusions and how
it's thinking about accomplishing this.
So the more you add tracing data like
how you for example like how we're
debugging these systems the more we show
users these kind of like internal
workings how these things are built how
they're evaluated how they think the
more trust they evolve and like it sets
expectations right to the right time. So
like the more like the more you see them
considering a lot of angles you never
considered before like storing secrets
in encrypted files and not like in plain
text and stuff like that the more you
realize okay these things are actually
more reliable than I thought and then
you would trust them more. Um so this is
one thing another thing we're doing is
we're starting like opening up like
these benchmark results. So the first
time we launched an agent last year uh
we published with it like a a big table
with what it's good at and what it sucks
at. As you can see like we added a row
um of like okay this cannot deploy
superbase like the success rate is zero
even after multiple trials. So we show
developers that you think like which
scenarios these are optimized for and
which scenarios we're evaluating for and
which other scenarios are still not very
explored and you can trust them to do
these kind of things well.
Got it. Nice. And then if I'm a
developer that hasn't done the DevOps
thing yet, do you feel like you the
world of AI makes this like more
approachable like would would you like
recommend that they actually start
getting into DevOps now and that you
know the water is warm?
Yes, definitely. Definitely. I mean like
a lot of developers I meet are scared of
doing infrastructure work because they
don't want to mess things something up
like they don't want to leave a firewall
rule open or like leave the database
public and so on. And you would see like
it's it's much easier to align like the
the like these kind of agents or like
these kind of chat bots or like the code
generation whatever you're doing with
specific security policies. So like the
defaults are really more secure than
what an average developer would do
because because developers are scared of
touching this kind of work but I think
now it's more manageable at least you
can think like you can check the thought
process uh of these agents and you can
do it yourself. But like it's it's very
educational. Like I've learned new AWS
CLI commands by watching these agents
work. I didn't know for example there's
a command subcomand for you to wait on a
specific resource to be ready. Like I
always wrote a bash script or like use
something else.
That's fun. Awesome. Well, George, thank
you so much for taking the time and
staying up late to uh to show us all of
this stuff. We really appreciate it and
look forward to chatting on Discord and
the like and continuing the
conversation.
Amazing. It's my pleasure. Happy to be
here. Thanks for having me. Yeah.
Cheers.